=Spring Fever= =Episode 2=
=حمى الربيع= =الحلقة الثانية=
I was healing at the temple.
كنت أتعافى في المعبد.
You shouted and drew my pursuers here,
لقد صرخت وجذبت مطاردي إلى هنا،
making my poison flare up.
جعل السم يشتعل.
So, you must take responsibility.
لذا، يجب عليك أن تتحمل المسؤولية.
If you had acted faster
لو تصرفت بشكل أسرع
against those two hooligans,
ضد هذين المشاغبين،
I wouldn't have drawn them here.
لم أرسمهم هنا.
Why blame me?
لماذا تلوموني؟
Besides,
بجانب،
I have no money
ليس لدي مال
or medical skills. How can I take responsibility?
أو المهارات الطبية. كيف أتحمل المسؤولية؟
Suck my Gu poison out.
امتص السم الخاص بي.
You're shameless!
أنت وقح!
Shameless. Just kill me.
بلا خجل. اقتلني فقط.
Of course, I won't kill you.
بالطبع لن أقتلك.
But I will certainly investigate
ولكنني سأحقق بالتأكيد
which family dares
أي عائلة تجرؤ؟
harbor criminal slaves.
إيواء العبيد المجرمين.
Stop struggling.
توقف عن النضال.
Just give in to me.
فقط استسلم لي.
Let go of me.
أتركني.
According to the law,
وفقا للقانون،
harboring criminal slaves warrants
مذكرات إيواء العبيد المجرمين
extermination of nine clans.
إبادة تسعة عشائر.
Since we can't see each other now,
نظرًا لأننا لا نستطيع رؤية بعضنا البعض الآن،
I won't blame you for your offense.
لن ألومك على جريمتك.
(I can't die yet.)
(لا أستطيع أن أموت بعد.)
(Shi'an and Jin are waiting. I must go home.)
(شيآن وجين ينتظران. يجب أن أعود إلى المنزل.)
♪I'll sweep through dusty sands♪
♪سأمسح الرمال المتربة♪
♪Passing wind♪
♪ريح عابرة♪
♪Entwine my hair in dance♪
♪تشابك شعري في الرقص♪
♪I'll lean into his embrace♪
♪سأستند إلى حضنه♪
♪Wade through deep seas♪
♪خوض البحار العميقة♪
♪Bathing in affection♪
♪الاستحمام في المودة♪
♪Condensing into rain♪
♪تكثف إلى مطر♪
Hey.
يا.
Hey. Wake up.
مهلا، استيقظ.
(Did he die?)
(هل مات؟)
(Will the officials trace this to me?)
(هل سيصلني المسؤولون عن هذا الأمر؟)
Hey.
يا.
Wake up.
استيقظ.
(Thank god. He's alive.)
(الحمد لله أنه على قيد الحياة.)
Hey.
يا.
Are you okay?
هل أنت بخير؟
Then I'll leave now.
سأغادر الآن.
(Why is he delirious?)
(لماذا هو هذياني؟)
(Did I fail to fully remove the love poison?)
(هل فشلت في إزالة سم الحب بشكل كامل؟)
Get off!
ترجل!
My lord.
سيدي.
Gao Fu.
جاو فو.
You've finally awakened.
لقد استيقظت أخيرا.
You were poisoned,
لقد تم تسميمك
but luckily,
ولكن لحسن الحظ،
it was removed timely.
لقد تمت إزالته في الوقت المناسب.
You're fine now.
أنت بخير الآن.
When you arrived last night,
عندما وصلت الليلة الماضية،
did I behave improperly?
هل تصرفت بشكل غير لائق؟
(Gao Fu, Censor) When I arrived,
(جاو فو، الرقيب) عندما وصلت،
corpses were everywhere.
وكانت الجثث في كل مكان.
When I found you,
عندما وجدتك
this lady was calling out to you.
هذه السيدة كانت تنادي عليك.
Fearing she was an assassin, I detained her
خوفًا من أن تكون قاتلة، قمت باحتجازها
and awaited your command.
وانتظر أمرك.
So she and I...
إذن هي وأنا...
Nothing happened between us.
لم يحدث بيننا شئ .
Last night, you begged me to detoxify you.
لقد توسلت إليّ ليلة أمس أن أقوم بإزالة السموم منك.
Then you suddenly went mad.
ثم فجأة أصبحت مجنونا.
During the struggle,
أثناء النضال،
you collapsed unconscious.
لقد انهارت فاقدا للوعي.
I thought you died,
اعتقدت أنك مت
so I kept calling out to you.
لذلك واصلت مناداتك.
And then he arrived.
ثم وصل.
Right.
يمين.
Good.
جيد.
But why did you ask it, my lord?
ولكن لماذا سألت ذلك يا سيدي؟
No reason.
لا يوجد سبب.
Have you identified those assassins?
هل تعرفت على هؤلاء القتلة؟
We eliminated
لقد تخلصنا
all ambushers outside.
جميع الكمائن بالخارج.
We kept one alive.
لقد أبقينا واحدا على قيد الحياة.
But I didn't expect he would kill himself, leaving no information.
ولكنني لم أتوقع أنه سيقتل نفسه دون أن يترك أي معلومة.
However, they all had a tattoo on their hands.
ومع ذلك، كان جميعهم لديهم وشم على أيديهم.
Here's the pattern.
وهنا النمط.
But no records match it in our archives.
ولكن لا يوجد أي سجل يطابق ذلك في أرشيفاتنا.
It seems Ningzhou Prefecture is really extraordinary.
يبدو أن محافظة نينغتشو غير عادية حقًا.
Perhaps,
ربما،
this tattoo could be our breakthrough.
قد يكون هذا الوشم بمثابة اختراق لنا.
Figure it out right away.
اعرف ذلك على الفور.
Yes.
نعم.
My lord.
سيدي.
This lady...
هذه السيدة...
- Silence her. - Yes.
- أسكتها. - نعم.
Wait.
انتظر.
You have last words?
هل لديك كلمات أخيرة؟
I've seen this tattoo before.
لقد رأيت هذا الوشم من قبل.
Where did you see it?
أين رأيته؟
I was framed.
لقد تم تأطيري.
Returning would be dangerous.
العودة ستكون خطيرة.
Only you can help me.
أنت فقط من يمكنه مساعدتي.
Resolve my problem at the Lu family on Xiaowen Road tomorrow noon.
سيتم حل مشكلتي في منزل عائلة لو في شارع شياوين غدًا ظهرًا.
And I'll tell you.
وسأخبرك.
You dare threaten me?
هل تجرؤ على تهديدي؟
Consider your status first.
خذ حالتك في الاعتبار أولاً.
My status doesn't matter.
حالتي لا تهم.
What matters is
ما يهم هو
that I know
أني أعرف
what you want to know.
ما تريد أن تعرفه.
(As you wished, I'm here.)
(كما أردت، أنا هنا.)
(Imperial decree)
(المرسوم الإمبراطوري)
I'm Prefect of Ningzhou.
أنا حاكم نينغتشو.
Greetings, my lord.
تحياتي سيدي.
- Greetings, my lord.
- تحياتي سيدي.
Your visit here is...
زيارتك هنا هي...
Has the Young Lord from the Duke Xuan's Mansion
هل كان اللورد الشاب من قصر الدوق شوان
already arrived in Ningzhou?
وصلت بالفعل إلى نينغتشو؟
Gao Fu.
جاو فو.
Open it.
افتحه.
Watch out.
احذر.
Lord Xia.
اللورد شيا.
The Young Lord was returning to Bianzhou to visit family
كان الشاب اللورد عائدا إلى بيانتشو لزيارة العائلة
and stopped to rest in Ningzhou Prefecture.
وتوقف للراحة في محافظة نينغتشو.
Before he'd even left the capital,
حتى قبل أن يغادر العاصمة،
assassins were already lying in wait.
وكان القتلة يتربصون بالفعل.
Had I not led the vanguard,
لو لم أقود الطليعة،
this blade would have been plunged into his body.
لقد تم غرس هذا النصل في جسده.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
who exactly is it
من هو بالضبط
that wants the Young Lord dead so desperately?
الذي يريد قتل اللورد الشاب بشدة؟
I will order an investigation immediately.
سأطلب إجراء تحقيق على الفور.
I'll find out swiftly
سأعرف ذلك بسرعة
and give you a full account.
وأعطيك حسابًا كاملاً.
Lord Xia.
اللورد شيا.
I've searched all over Ningzhou
لقد بحثت في جميع أنحاء نينغتشو
looking for you.
أبحث عنك.
I'm exhausted now.
أنا مرهق الآن.
Conduct the investigation here.
أجري التحقيق هنا.
I'll be waiting.
سوف انتظر.
Yes.
نعم.
You seem
يبدو أنك
somewhat familiar to me.
مألوفة بالنسبة لي إلى حد ما.
Lord Shen,
اللورد شين،
she is my concubine.
إنها محظيتي.
She rarely ventures out.
نادرا ما تخرج.
You must be mistaken.
لابد أنك مخطئ.
What crime
ما هي الجريمة
has she committed?
هل ارتكبت جريمة؟
My lord,
سيدي،
this vile woman committed adultery at the Goddess Temple last night,
لقد ارتكبت هذه المرأة الحقيرة جريمة الزنا في معبد الإلهة الليلة الماضية،
defiling the gods
تدنيس الآلهة
and causing me to lose my child.
ويسبب لي فقدان طفلي.
She deserves death!
إنها تستحق الموت!
Lan,
و،
I don't regret loving you sincerely.
لا أندم على حبي لك بصدق.
We were just bound by longing,
لقد كنا مقيدين بالشوق فقط،
but not by fate.
ولكن ليس بالقدر.
Then I wasn't mistaken.
إذن لم أكن مخطئا.
When I was attacked in the temple yesterday,
عندما تعرضت للهجوم في المعبد أمس،
you were also there.
لقد كنت هناك أيضا.
Yesterday, when assassins came for me
بالأمس، عندما جاء القتلة من أجلي
and chased me into the temple,
وطاردوني إلى المعبد،
I saw her lighting lamps alone.
رأيتها تضيء المصابيح بمفردها.
She got caught in the battle because of me.
لقد وقعت في المعركة بسببي.
If I recall correctly,
إذا كنت أتذكر بشكل صحيح،
all the assassins
كل القتلة
should have been slain by me.
كان ينبغي أن أقتله.
So I'd like to ask
لذلك أود أن أسأل
how he got away unscathed?
كيف نجا دون أن يصاب بأذى؟
Well...
حسنًا...
My lord,
سيدي،
could it be
هل يمكن أن يكون
he's in league with the assassins?
هل هو متحالف مع القتلة؟
Perfect.
ممتاز.
We've got one empty cage left.
لقد بقي لدينا قفص فارغ.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
Lord Xia.
اللورد شيا.
How about
ماذا عن
I sever this escaped assassin's head
سأقطع رأس هذا القاتل الهارب
and deliver it to you?
وأوصلها إليك؟
How's that?
كيف ذلك؟
No.
لا.
My lord!
سيدي!
- I'm innocent, my lord! - Shut up!
- أنا بريء يا سيدي! - اسكت!
Guards! Take him away.
أيها الحراس! خذوه بعيدًا.
Lady Jinzhi, you promised me...
السيدة جينزي، لقد وعدتني...
My lord.
سيدي.
Xia Jinzhi believes
يعتقد شيا جين تشى أن هذا هو ما يعتقده
my failure to light her blessing lamp in the temple
فشلي في إضاءة مصباح بركاتها في المعبد
caused her child to die.
تسبب في وفاة طفلها.
But I think
ولكنني أعتقد
her child's death
وفاة طفلها
has no connection to whether I lit lamps or not.
ليس له علاقة بكوني أشعلت المصابيح أم لا.
My lord,
سيدي،
you know perfectly well
أنت تعرف جيدا
whether I committed adultery last night, right?
هل ارتكبت الزنا الليلة الماضية، أليس كذلك؟
Shut up!
اسكت!
You killed my son!
لقد قتلت ابني!
Whether you committed adultery
هل ارتكبت الزنا
is certainly clear to me.
من الواضح بالنسبة لي.
However,
لكن،
the notion that lamp-lighting
فكرة أن إضاءة المصباح
harmed a fetus is pure nonsense.
إن إيذاء الجنين هو محض هراء.
In my judgment,
في حكمي،
the deceased should be autopsied, and the living one has check-up.
يجب تشريح جثة المتوفى، وإجراء فحص طبي للحي.
We'll get to the bottom of it today.
سوف نصل إلى حقيقة الأمر اليوم.
♪Grind flesh between grit and stone♪
♪طحن اللحم بين الحصى والحجر♪
♪Sink into pain, only then are pearls born♪
♪الغرق في الألم، حينها فقط تولد اللآلئ♪
♪Wait until abyssal darkness stains every inch of skin♪
♪انتظر حتى يلطخ الظلام السحيق كل شبر من الجلد♪
♪Then comes the time to chase the dawn♪
♪ثم يأتي الوقت لمطاردة الفجر♪
♪I'll sweep through dusty sands♪
♪سأمسح الرمال المتربة♪
♪Passing wind♪
♪ريح عابرة♪
♪Entwine my hair in dance♪
♪تشابك شعري في الرقص♪
♪I'll lean into his embrace♪
♪سأستند إلى حضنه♪
♪Wade through deep seas♪
♪خوض البحار العميقة♪
♪Bathing in affection♪
♪الاستحمام في المودة♪
♪Condensing into rain♪
♪تكثف إلى مطر♪
♪Who cast a frantic, lingering glance♪
♪الذي ألقى نظرة محمومة ومتباطئة♪
♪Carrying endless tenderness♪
♪تحمل حنانًا لا نهاية له♪
♪Gazing through eons of moonlit winds♪
♪التحديق عبر عصور من الرياح المضاءة بالقمر♪
♪Turn tears to pearls and cradle them within♪
♪حوّل الدموع إلى لآلئ واحتضنها في داخلك♪
♪Henceforth we walk the mortal realm♪
♪من الآن فصاعدا نسير في عالم البشر♪
♪Across vast mountains and rivers♪
♪عبر الجبال والأنهار الشاسعة♪
♪I'll sweep through dusty sands♪
♪سأمسح الرمال المتربة♪
♪Passing wind♪
♪ريح عابرة♪
♪Entwine my hair in dance♪
♪تشابك شعري في الرقص♪
♪I'll lean into his embrace♪
♪سأستند إلى حضنه♪
♪Wade through deep seas♪
♪خوض البحار العميقة♪
♪Bathing in affection♪
♪الاستحمام في المودة♪
♪Condensing into rain♪
♪تكثف إلى مطر♪